Guide to the South Africa Now Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Other Network Footage, 1985-1991, undated; Series VIII
  - Tapes J95-J96: ABC Town Meeting - Nightline in South Africa with Koppel and Mandela, 1990 February 14-16; 2 (Box 1951–1952)
  - Tape J97: WTN -- South Africa talks and African National Congress (ANC), 1990 August 6; 1 (Box 1953)
  - Tape J98: De Klerk meets church members, 1989 December 11; 1 (Box 1954)
  - Tape J99: Nightline -- Mandela Interview, 1990 February 15; 1 (Box 1955)
  - Tape J100: Gil Noble, "Like It Is" -- interview with ex-CIA officer John Stockwell, Undated; 1 (Box 1956)
  - Tape J101: WTN -- Defiance Campaign -- beaches, 1989 August 29; 1 (Box 1957)
  - Tape J103: "One Country, Two Worlds," history of South Africa -- stills, maps, interviews, 1990 April 1-5; 1 (Box 1958)
  - Tape J104: "Steps Toward Freedom," Carol Simpson special on South Africa, 1990 April 20; 1 (Box 1959)
  - Tape J105: Nightline -- South Africa day 2 - Defiance 89, 1990 February 8; 1 (Box 1960)
  - Tape J106: McNeil/Lehrer NewsHour -- Conservative Party, Undated; 1 (Box 1961)
  - Tape J107: WTN Tom Lodge interview, 1990 March 31-April 1; 1 (Box 1962)
  - Tape J108: Botswana record store exteriors; Ambassadors reception, Undated; 1 (Box 1963)
  - Tape J109: McNeil/Lehrer NewsHour -- media censorship, Undated; 1 (Box 1964)
  - Tape J110: South Africa right wing, 1989 August 16; 1 (Box 1965)
  - Tape J111: Off-air taping of network news, 1990 September 23; 1 (Box 1966)
  - Tape J112: De Klerk to Washington, Winnie to court, 1990 September 24; 1 (Box 1967)
  - Tape J113: SABC -- Chief Maphumulo murder, 1991 April 30; 1 (Box 1968)
  - Tape J114: Ciskei footage, WTN, Undated; 1 (Box 1969)
  - Tape J115: Mandela leaves prison (ABC), 1990 February 11; 1 (Box 1970)
  - Tape J116: Sisulu in Transkei; tear gas in church, [No year] December 25; 1 (Box 1971)
  - Tape J117: "McLaughin" Joseph Labonte segments, 1990 October 17; 1 (Box 1972)
- Jesse Jackson Diaries, 1986 August; Series IX
  The series includes footage that documents Jesse Jackson's efforts to fight apartheid.
  Original audio, film, and video recordings, as well as preservation masters and duplicating masters may not be played. Readers may only play use copies. If a use copy of a particular recording does not exist, researchers must consult with the reference archivist for policies and procedures regarding the creation of duplicating master and use copies of original recordings.
  - Tape JJ1: Botswana -- Masire and Jackson at conference table; shaking hands, holding book; Sun City Hotel; market; city; countryside with houses; flag; book centre; students; newspaper; Jesse and minister; music store, 1986 August; 1 (Box 1973)
  - Tape JJ2: Angola -- interview with JAckson at presidential palace, 1986 August 18; 1 (Box 1974)
  - Tape JJ3: Angola -- car going to orphanage, 1986 August; 1 (Box 1975)
  - Tape JJ4: Angola -- leaving Angola; airport and president's palace; joint statement, 1986 August; 1 (Box 1976)
  - Tape JJ5: Tanzania -- university speech, 1 (Box 1977)
  - Tape JJ6: Nigeria -- banquet, 1986 August; 1 (Box 1978)
  - Tape JJ7: Angola -- Jackson's banquet with president, 1986 August 16; 1 (Box 1979)
  - Tape JJ8: Angola -- president's reception, entrance, other leaders, banquet, 1986 August 16; 1 (Box 1980)
  - Tape JJ9: United States -- airport, 1986 August; 1 (Box 1981)
  - Tape JJ10: Zambia -- church service; market place, 1986 August; 1 (Box 1982)
  - Tape JJ11: Zambia -- church singing and sermon, 1986 August; 1 (Box 1983)
  - Tape JJ12: Angola -- reception at airport; press conference; tomb of soldier; streets, 1986 August 16; 1 (Box 1984)
- United Nations TV, 1988-1989, undated; Series X
  The series includes footage taken from United Nations television coverage of South African topics. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape K1: South Africa; press conference on execution of Sharpeville 6; Intern Day and Sarafina, 1988 March 8, 17, 21; 1 (Box 1985)
  - Tape K2: Special Committee Against Apartheid; United Nations (UN) Council for Namibia; Special Committee Against Apartheid, 1988 May 6; 1 (Box 1986)
  - Tape K3: Special Committee Against Apartheid; Tutu; Garba, 1988 May 6; 1 (Box 1987)
  - Tape K4: Special Committee Against Apartheid, 1988 June 30; 1 (Box 1988)
  - Tape K5: Suliman; Sugar Ray Leonard, 1988 June 30; 1 (Box 1989)
    Parts of the tape do not contain audio.
  - Tape K7: Soweto Day; spokesperson on Sharpeville 6, 1988 July 1; 1 (Box 1990)
  - Tape K9: Lt. General Ndaulu, Angola, 1988 July 13; 1 (Box 1991)
  - Tape K10: Stevie Wonder honored by Committee Against Apartheid, 1985 May 13; 1 (Box 1992)
  - Tape K11: Jesse Jackson press conference, 1988 July 13; 1 (Box 1993)
  - Tape K12: International Day of Solidarity with Political Prisoners -- Prakash Diar, 1988 October 11; 1 (Box 1994)
  - Tape K13: General Assembly session: Angola -- Afonso Van Dunem M'Binda, 1988 October 13; 1 (Box 1995)
  - Tape K14: Tripartite signing ceremony; press conference -- Cuba; General Assembly, 1988 December 22; 1 (Box 1996)
  - Tape K15: General Assembly -- economic matters; Security Council -- Namibia verification mission, 1988 December 20; 1 (Box 1997)
  - Tape K16: Press conference Angola; press conference South Africa; photo opportunities, Undated; 1 (Box 1998)
  - Tape K17: Peacekeeping highlights, 1988 September 29; 1 (Box 1999)
  - Tape K18: Security Council -- Namibia, 1988 September 29; 1 (Box 2000)
  - Tape K20: United Nations (UN) Council for Namibia, 1988 October 14; 1 (Box 2001)
  - Tape K21: Photo opportunity, Guinea; United Nations (UN) speech on peacekeeping; General Assembly -- South Africa, 1988 October 26; 1 (Box 2002)
  - Tape K22: Jesse Jackson -- United Nations (UN) Council for Namibia, solidarity with people of Namibia, 1988 October 27; 1 (Box 2003)
  - Tape K23: Security Council on 435 vote, Namibia; Secretary General's press conference, 1989 February 16; 1 (Box 2004)
  - Tapes K24-K25: Martii Ahtisaari, 1988 October 13; 2 (Box 2005–2006)
  - Tape K26: Mugabe press conference, 1988 September 15; 1 (Box 2007)
  - Tape K27: International Day for Elimination of Racial Discrimination -- exhibit: Apartheid South Africa, 1989 March 21; 1 (Box 2008)
  - Tape K28: Debt Crisis: African Dilemma (Zambia), 1988 November 8; 1 (Box 2009)
  - Tape K29: Security consultations [re: Namibia], 1989 April 3; 1 (Box 2010)
  - Tape K30: Special Committee Against Apartheid, 1989 April 6; 1 (Box 2011)
  - Tape K31: Security Council: Namibia, 1989 April 7; 1 (Box 2012)
  - Tape K32: Security Council: Namibia, 1989 August 17; 1 (Box 2013)
  - Tape K35: Reagan on United Nations (UN) 40th Anniversary; treaty signing (Cuba, Angola, U.S.), 1989 January 24; 1 (Box 2014)
  - Tapes K36-K37: Hearings -- oil embargo against South Africa; International Court of Justice (ICJ) press conference, 1989 April 12-13; 2 (Box 2015–2016)
  - Tape K38: Secretary General's comments on Namibia, 1989 October [4]; 1 (Box 2017)
  - Tape K39: Mothopeng -- African National Congress (ANC), 1989 June 15; 1 (Box 2018)
  - Tape K40: International Day of Solidarity to Women of South Africa and Namibia, 1989 August 9; 1 (Box 2019)
  - Tape K41: Press conference: African commodities, 1989 May 22; 1 (Box 2020)
  - Tape K42: Security Council: Namibia, 1989 August 21; 1 (Box 2021)
  - Tape K43: Special Committee Against Apartheid; Sisulu delegation at United Nations (UN), 1989 July 6; 1 (Box 2022)
  - Tape K44: "A Race Against Time: The Story of Sport Aid"; Sport Aid update; United Nations (UN) special session on Africa, Undated; 1 (Box 2023)
  - Tape K45: General Assembly -- President of Zaire, Mobutu, 1989 October 4; 1 (Box 2024)
  - Tape K46: General Assembly -- Lesotho, 1989 October 10; 1 (Box 2025)
  - Tape K47: General Assembly, International Day of Solidarity with South African Prisoners, 1989 October 11; 1 (Box 2026)
  - Tapes K48-K49: Security Council -- Namibia, 1989 August 7, 18; 2 (Box 2027–2028)
  - Tape K50: Jesse Jackson -- General Assembly, 1989 October 19; 1 (Box 2029)
  - Tape K51: Henry Bonzaire testimony -- General Assembly, 1989 October 23; 1 (Box 2030)
  - Tape K52: Security Council -- Namibia, 1989 November 1; 1 (Box 2031)
  - Tape K53: General Assembly; press conference, Pakistan; press conference, USSR, 1989 November 1; 1 (Box 2032)
  - Tape K54: 3rd Committee -- Social and Humanitarian Committee; press conference -- Sweden; noon briefing, 1989 November 2; 1 (Box 2033)
  - Tape K55: General Assembly -- Apartheid, 1989 November 7; 1 (Box 2034)
  - Tape K56: Apartheid; press conference -- demonstration in Korea; International Support and Verification Commission [Comisión Internacional de Apoyo y Verificación] (CIAV) talks, 1989 November 9; 1 (Box 2035)
  - Tape K57: Ambassador of South Africa [re: Namibia], 1989 November 14; 1 (Box 2036)
  - Tape K58: Secretary General statement [re: Namibian elections], Undated; 1 (Box 2037)
  - Tape K59: Namibia rolls, 1989 November 27; 1 (Box 2038)
  - Tape K60: General Assembly -- Mugabe; Garba; Kaunda, 1989 December 12; 1 (Box 2039)
  - Tape K62: United Nations (UN) Ad Hoc Committee on Apartheid; Dinkins; Boesak; Max Coleman, 1989 December 13; 2 (Box 2040–2041)
    The same tape number was assigned to recordings of two segments of this meeting.
  - Tapes K63-K64: General Assembly -- apartheid; press conference -- Namibia; General Assembly vote -- apartheid, 1989 December 14; 2 (Box 2042–2043)
- Stills, 1988-1990, undated; Series XI
  The series consists of video recordings of still photography of individuals, locations, and events documented in the production of South Africa Now. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape L26: Stills (also on Tape F174); close up for Shaka Zulu, 1988 November 21; 1 (Box 2044)
  - Tape L27: Shaka Zulu; Ron Wilkins, 1988 November 15; 1 (Box 2045)
  - Tape L27: Stills, show #206, Undated; 1 (Box 2046)
  - Tapes L28-L29: Township art, 1988 November 24; 2 (Box 2047–2048)
    See also: Tapes L63-L64, boxes 2080-2081.
  - Tape L30: Weekly Mail; Reebok Human Rights awardees, Undated; 1 (Box 2049)
  - Tape L31: Dumile, 1988 December 8; 1 (Box 2050)
  - Tape L32: In-studio o/c [on camera?] for #111: Mweli and Carolyn; "Africa Report" cover, 1988 December 12; 1 (Box 2051)
  - Tape L33: Stills for #111, 1988 December 12; 1 (Box 2052)
  - Tape L34: Stills for #202, Undated; 1 (Box 2053)
  - Tapes L35-L36: "Cordoned Heart", 1989 February 2; 2 (Box 2054–2055)
    See also: Tape L42, box 2061.
  - Tape L37: Mandela, Undated; 1 (Box 2056)
  - Tapes L38-L40: Winnie Mandela stills, Undated; 3 (Box 2057–2059)
  - Tape L41: Namibia, Undated; 1 (Box 2060)
  - Tape L42: "Cordoned Heart", 1989 February 2; 1 (Box 2061)
    See also: Tapes L35-L36, boxes 2054-2055.
  - Tape L43: Le Cirque; New York Post, 1989 February 13; 1 (Box 2062)
  - Tapes L44-L46: South Africa Now lobby, Undated; 3 (Box 2063–2065)
  - Tape L47: "Vlok's Prison Strike Crisis", Undated; 1 (Box 2066)
  - Tape L48: Human Rights Report, Undated; 1 (Box 2067)
  - Tape L50: Modeling, Undated; 1 (Box 2068)
  - Tapes L52-L53: Israel, Undated; 2 (Box 2069–2070)
  - Tape L54: Stills for #207, Undated; 1 (Box 2071)
  - Tape L55: Carnegie, Undated; 1 (Box 2072)
  - Tape L56: Spy piece, Undated; 1 (Box 2073)
  - Tape L57: Thatcher -- Pretoria, 1989 March 31; 1 (Box 2074)
  - Tapes L58-L59: South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO) -- dead photos, Undated; 2 (Box 2075–2076)
  - Tape L60: Mobil stills, Undated; 1 (Box 2077)
  - Tape L61: Headlines of South African newspapers; Washington reception photographs; Michelle Shocked; Shapiro; Weekly Mail; Wayne Steiner, Undated; 1 (Box 2078)
  - Tape L62: Stills of South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO) dead -- blow ups, Undated; 1 (Box 2079)
  - Tapes L63-L64: Township art, Undated; 2 (Box 2080–2081)
    See also: Tapes L28-L29, boxes 2047-2048.
  - Tape L65: Jonathan Shapiro, Undated; 1 (Box 2082)
  - Tapes L66, L114-L115: Soweto, Undated; 3 (Box 2083–2085)
  - Tape L116: Funeral images, 1990 July 22; 1 (Box 2086)
  - Tape L117: Mozambique, Undated; 1 (Box 2087)
  - Tape L118: Mozambique and Namibia, Undated; 1 (Box 2088)
  - Tapes L119-L121: Hit squads, 1990, undated; 3 (Box 2089–2091)
  - Tape L122: Mandela release, Undated; 1 (Box 2092)
  - Tape L123: Press restrictions, 1990 February 8; 1 (Box 2093)
  - Tape L124: African National Congress (ANC), 1990 January 8; 1 (Box 2094)
  - Tape L125: Tambo and Mandela, Undated; 1 (Box 2095)
  - Tape L126: Danny Schechter visa rejection, Undated; 1 (Box 2096)
  - Tape L127: East Europeans moving to South Africa, Undated; 1 (Box 2097)
  - Tape L128: Armed Forces magazine; South Africa magazine, Undated; 1 (Box 2098)
  - Tape L129: Stills for #505: Violence, Undated; 1 (Box 2099)
  - Tape L130: De Klerk, 1990 September 24; 1 (Box 2100)
  - Tape L131: Malcolm X, Undated; 1 (Box 2101)
    See also: Tape L133, box 2103 and Tape L136, box 2106.
  - Tape L132: unidentified (Stills tape [2] Diane -- Malcolm X?), Undated; 1 (Box 2102)
  - Tape L133: Malcolm X, 1990 October 19; 1 (Box 2103)
    See also: Tape L131, box 2101 and Tape L136, box 2106.
  - Tape L134: Children On the Frontline, Undated; 1 (Box 2104)
  - Tape L135: Mirror at midnight; worker's charter, Undated; 1 (Box 2105)
  - Tape L136: Malcolm X, Undated; 1 (Box 2106)
    See also: Tape L131, box 2101 and Tape L133, box 2103.
  - Tape L137: National Indian Congress, Undated; 1 (Box 2107)
- Miscellaneous PAL Tapes, 1988-1990, undated; Series XII
  The series consists of videotapes using the European PAL standard, that document a wide range of South African political, social, and cultural events. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape M1: Qwa Qwa, Undated; 1 (Box 2108)
  - Tape M2: Reverend Frank Chikane interview, Undated; 1 (Box 2109)
  - Tape M3: B-roll of commuters, Johannesburg and Rapitsi, South Africa, Undated; 1 (Box 2110)
  - Tape M7: Music videos: Mercy Pakela -- "Mafia" and African Youth Band -- "Vuka"; poverty b-roll -- Botshabelo in Free State near Qwa Qwa, 1984, undated; 1 (Box 2111)
  - Tape M8: Senator Paul Simon; Don Stillman, United Auto Workers (UAW), Undated; 1 (Box 2112)
  - Tape M10: Viz News, BBC, James Robbins reporting on 40 years of National Party rule, with clips from 1948; reports on other countries, 1988 May 24; 1 (Box 2113)
  - Tape M11: Detainees released; Interview with Gabu Tagwana; demonstration in Johannesburg, 1989 February 23; 1 (Box 2114)
  - Tape M12: National Union of South African Students (NUSAS) conference; Murphy Morobe, 1989 February 22; 1 (Box 2115)
  - Tape M13: Hillbrow Hospital; lawyers press conference, 1989 February 22; 1 (Box 2116)
  - Tape M14: Hunger strike, including Montsisi father, strikers, Chikane, 1989 February 23; 1 (Box 2117)
    The audio on the tape is poor.
  - Tape M15: African National Congress (ANC) Video Unit, 1989 January 17; 1 (Box 2118)
  - Tape M16: Ameen Akhalwaya, 1989 February 1; 1 (Box 2119)
  - Tape M17: Cartonville; Detainees Day, 1989 March 15; 1 (Box 2120)
  - Tape M18: National Detainees Day, 1989 March 15; 1 (Box 2121)
  - Tape M19: The Deeper Image, Debonair Productions, 1989 March 17; 1 (Box 2122)
  - Tape M21: Savimbi, 1989 March 23; 1 (Box 2123)
  - Tapes M22-M23: Eddie; Wits (University of the Witwatersrand) press conference, 1989 March 23; 2 (Box 2124–2125)
  - Tape M25: Namibia, 1989 April 1; 1 (Box 2126)
  - Tape M33: Ramaphosa, Undated; 1 (Box 2126A)
  - Tape M32: Hunger strike press conference, 1989 April 2; 1 (Box 2127)
  - Tape M34: Doxa Productions: shots of Capetown, Athlone House; bus station; Boesak and Tutu teaching, 1986 December 4; 1 (Box 2128)
  - Tape M35: Mobil stations -- Johannesburg, 1989 April 29; 1 (Box 2128A)
  - Tape M36: Media Show -- Condun, England, 1989 April 24; 1 (Box 2129)
  - Tape M37: Shell protests -- Amsterdam, 1989 May 1; 1 (Box 2130)
  - Tapes M38-M39: David Webster memorial service and press conference, 1989 May 8; 2 (Box 2131–2132)
  - Tape M40: Effects of the Bannings, 1988 April; 1 (Box 2133)
  - Tape M41: Stayaway -- Petermaritzburg, 1989 June 7; 1 (Box 2134)
  - Tape M41: Mozambique: doctors visit to Maputo hospital, Undated; 1 (Box 2135)
  - Tapes M42-M43: Press conference with Peter Mokaba, South African Youth Congress (SAYCO) president, 1989 June 13; 2 (Box 2136–2137)
  - Tape M47: Uppington -- Paballelo, 1989 June 23; 1 (Box 2138)
  - Tape M48: Uppington, 1989 June 23; 1 (Box 2139)
  - Tape M49: South African Medical Association (SAMA) -- press conference, 1989 June 23; 1 (Box 2140)
  - Tape M50: Thandeka Gqubule -- Weekly Mail, 1989 June 23; 1 (Box 2141)
  - Tape M51: Brenda Fasie, Undated; 1 (Box 2142)
  - Tape M52: Pioneer camp in Mazimbe, Morogoro, Tanzania; South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO) creek; SWAPO garment factory; transit camps; Interview with old member of SWAPO, 1989 June 28; 1 (Box 2143)
  - Tape M53: African National Congress (ANC) head of Women's Council; Interview, South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO); Amandela Cultural Group; ANC Head of Women, Gertrude Shope, addressing SWAPO farewell ceremony; presentation of gifts to SWAPO; vote of thanks to SWAPO, 1989 June 28; 1 (Box 2144)
  - Tape M55: Sample material from Doxa Productions on Alternative Afrikaners in South Africa, 1989 June 23; 1 (Box 2144A)
  - Tape M56: Voëlvry music video, 1989 June 29; 1 (Box 2145)
  - Tapes M57-M58: Inkatha Prayer for Peace Rally, 1989 June 25; 2 (Box 2146–2147)
  - Durban, Undated
    - Tape M59: Claremont, Gumede, 1 (Box 2148)
    - Tape M60: Abduction witnesses, 1 (Box 2149)
    - Tape M61: Lamontville, Inkatha at Kwamashu, 1 (Box 2150)
    - Tapes M62-M63: Buthelezi at Kwamashu, 2 (Box 2151–2152)
    - Tape M63: Gumede interview, 1 (Box 2152)
  - Tapes M64-M67: 5 Freedoms Forum meeting of African National Congress (ANC) in Lusaka, 1989 July 12; 4 (Box 2153–2156)
  - Tape M68: "Out of Sight, Out of Mind", 1989 May 9; 1 (Box 2157)
  - Tape M68: Congress of South African Trade Unions (COSATU) Conference compilation, Undated; 1 (Box 2158)
  - Tape M72: Bombing in Alexandra; press conference on Mass Democratic Movement, 1989 July 31; 1 (Box 2158A)
  - Tape M73: Highway with trucks, Johannesburg, 1989 July 28; 1 (Box 2159)
  - Tape M74: Valindaba (nuclear) Enrichment Plant (Pretoria), 1989 July 28; 1 (Box 2160)
  - Tape M76: South African Council of Churches, 1989 August 3; 1 (Box 2161)
  - Tape M77: Youth Resistance of Namibia; Namibia, 1989 August 8; 1 (Box 2162)
  - Tape M79: Mass Democratic Movement (MDM) Defiance Campaign -- desegregating hospitals, 1989 August 8; 1 (Box 2163)
  - Tape M80: Honger en Destabilisatie en Mozambique, 1988; 1 (Box 2164)
  - Tape M81: "Church in Namibia"; "End Conscription in South Africa", 1989; 1 (Box 2165)
  - Women's Day Cultural Rally
    - Tape M82: Women singers, North Transvaal; "Save the Children" singing; Mrs. Helen Joseph; Mrs. June Mlangeni, 1989 August 7; 1 (Box 2166)
    - Tape M83: Chairman -- United Democratic Front (UDF); Samora Machel; President of Transvaal Indian Congress (TIC); Multi-racial band; Sister Bernard, president of Federation of Transvaal Women (FEDTRAW), 1989 August 7; 1 (Box 2167)
  - Tape M84: "Namibia: The Future on a Balance"; "Youth Resistance in Namibia'; "End Conscription in South Africa"; churches, 1989 August; 1 (Box 2168)
  - Tape M85: Sister Bernard; Namibia solidarity; Boesak comments on tear gas; candelight procession, Undated; 1 (Box 2169)
  - Tape M86: Funeral of Watembach and Williams, 1989 August 14; 1 (Box 2170)
  - Tapes M88-M89: Inyanga Women's Day, 1989 August 15; 2 (Box 2171–2172)
  - Tape M90: Botha resignation speech, 1989 August 14; 1 (Box 2173)
  - Tape M91: Man on street (South Africa), Botha resigns, Undated; 1 (Box 2174)
  - Tape M92: "Each One Teach One", Undated; 1 (Box 2175)
  - Tape M97: Rand College anti-election campaign, 1989 August 17; 1 (Box 2175A)
  - Tape M103: Wynand Malan interview, Undated; 1 (Box 2176)
  - Tape M103: Interview with Van Slabbert, 1989 August 24; 1 (Box 2177)
  - Tape M104: Elections -- Vox Pops, Undated; 1 (Box 2178)
  - Tape M105: Congress of South African Trade Unions (COSATU) workers summit, 1989 August 26; 1 (Box 2179)
  - Tape M106: Arrest of Mohammed Valli Moosa; Interview with BBC and Murphy Morobe, 1989 August 18; 1 (Box 2180)
  - Tape M107: Elections -- posters, 1989 August; 1 (Box 2181)
  - Tapes M109-M111: Inyanga cast (Interviews), Undated; 3 (Box 2182–2184)
  - Tape M112: Elections defiance compilation, 1989 September 7; 1 (Box 2185)
  - Tape M113: Mass defiance at Wits (University of the Witwatersrand) and Cape Town, 1989 September 7; 1 (Box 2186)
  - Tape M116: Interview with Mark Swilling, 1989 September 7; 1 (Box 2187)
  - Tape M117: Afrovision -- 1989 election defiance, 1989 September 7; 1 (Box 2188)
  - Tape M118: Lenasia -- Merit Party candidate; Vox Pops, Hillbrow, 1989 September 7; 1 (Box 2189)
  - Tapes M121-M122: TNC -- closing press conference, 1989 September 6; 2 (Box 2190–2191)
  - Tape M125: TNC -- Barney Pityana, World Council of Churches, 1989 September 6; 2 (Box 2192)
  - Tape M126: African National Congress (ANC) meeting of writers held at Victoria Falls, Undated; 1 (Box 2193)
  - Tape M127: Mrs. Albertina Sisulu in Lusaka, 1989 July 21; 1 (Box 2194)
  - Tape M128: "Amandla -- A Complete Show", African National Congress (ANC), Undated; 1 (Box 2195)
  - Tape M129: Namibia: Interview with Gwen Lister concerning Anton Lubowski's death and press conference, Undated; 1 (Box 2196)
  - Tape M130: Nujoma, Sam -- Namibia, 1 (Box 2197)
  - Tape M131: Policeman Rochman interview re: demonstrations, Undated; 1 (Box 2198)
  - Tape M132: Rally at St. Mary's Cathedral, Johannesburg and prayer service, 1989 September 15; 1 (Box 2199)
  - Tape M133: Anton Lubowski -- memorial service at University of Namibia, Undated; 1 (Box 2200)
  - Tape M134: Anton Lubowski's house; Windhoek; Andimba Toiuo ya Toiuo; Theo ben Gurirab; Hidopo Hamutenya, Undated; 1 (Box 2201)
  - Tape M135: Sam Nujoma welcome home -- Namibia, Undated; 1 (Box 2202)
  - Tape M137: Cape Town march, led by mayor and religious leaders, 1989; 1 (Box 2203)
  - Tape M138: Cape Town demonstration and rally, Undated; 1 (Box 2204)
  - Tape M340: Fred Eckhardt, 1989 September 19; 1 (Box 2205)
  - Tape M341: Sam Nujoma rally, 1989 September 23; 1 (Box 2206)
  - Tape M342: Anton Lubowski funeral, 1989 October 1; 1 (Box 2207)
  - Tape M344: Walter Sisulu, Ahmed Kathrada addressing students, 1989 October 18; 1 (Box 2208)
  - Tapes M345-M346: Walter Sisulu interview; Ahmed Kathrada interview, 1989 October 19; 2 (Box 2209–2210)
    The audio on Tape M345 (box 2209) is defective for the first six minutes of the tape.
  - Tape M352: Namibian victory; announcement of results; Nujoma press conference, 1989 November 20; 1 (Box 2211)
  - Tape M355: Election footage, 1989 November 11, 18; 1 (Box 2212)
  - Tape M355: Harry Gwala interview, 1989 August 27; 1 (Box 2213)
  - Tape M356: Constitutional Assembly, 1989 November 21; 1 (Box 2214)
  - Tape M359: Peelton, 1989 December 6; 1 (Box 2215)
  - Tape M360: Compilation -- police and troops in action, 1986-1987; 1 (Box 2216)
  - Tape M361: Tele-Cine, Makhalipile (Trevor Huddleston biography), Undated; 1 (Box 2217)
  - Tape M362: Conference for a Democratic Future (CDF), 1989 December 9; 1 (Box 2218)
  - Tapes M363-M364: Two Dogs and Freedom, 1988 September 12; 2 (Box 2219–2220)
  - Tape M367: Winnie Mandela visits Nelson Mandela outside prison, 1989 December 29; 1 (Box 2221)
  - Tape M368: Winnie Mandela, 1989 December; 1 (Box 2222)
  - Tape M369: Winne Mandela and other interview, 1989 December; 1 (Box 2223)